Ted Hughes papers, 1940-1999
Emory University
- Photographs, circa 1910-1995, Series 7; Boxes 177-179; OP102, 115-117
  - Mexborough, South Yorkshire, Ted Hughes's second home (from 13 September 1938 to 13 September 1951) above the family newsagent’s shop, now a furniture shop (photographer: Terry Gifford) (Box 179, Folder 38)
  - No. 1 Aspinal Street, Mytholmroyd, West Yorkshire, Ted Hughes's first home (photographer: Terry Gifford) (Box 179, Folder 39)
  - Sheep and crow (Box 179, Folder 40)
  - Contact sheets
  - Miscellaneous contact sheets (2 x ca. 1970s and 2 x ca. 1960s) (Box 179, Folder 41)
  - "No Other Appetite: Sylvia Plath, Ted Hughes, and the Blood Jet of Poetry," exhibition at the Grolier Club of New York, 2005
  - 12 reproductions of photographs (Box OP117)
- Personal effects and memorabilia, Series 8; Boxes 180-181; OP118-119
  The series consists of personal effects and memorabilia relating to Ted Hughes and Sylvia Plath and their children, Frieda and Nicholas Hughes. The materials include Hughes's Royal Air Force Certificate of Service; an account book (1964-1967) documenting monies realized from the sale Hughes's poems; Hughes's permit to exit and re-enter U.S. (1959); marriage certificate (Ted Hughes and Sylvia Plath, 1957); Sylvia Plath's passport (1959), British Driving License, 1961 and death certificate (1963).
  The collection also includes William Henry Hughes's (father) World War I scrapbook containing newspaper clippings and photographs.
  - Personal effects
  - Hughes, Frieda, School work, writing (Box 180, Folder 1)
  - Hughes, Nicholas, Artwork (Box 180, Folder 2)
  - Hughes, Nicholas, Baptismal certificate, March 25, 1962 (Box 180, Folder 3)
  - Hughes, Nicholas, Christmas card, n.d. (Box 180, Folder 4)
  - Hughes, Nicholas, Report on Lates (fish species), TS (Box 180, Folder 5)
  - Hughes, Nicholas, school work, writing (Box 180, Folder 6)
  - Hughes, Ted, Account book, March 1964-December 1967 [documents monies realized from the sale of poems] (Box 180, Folder 7)
  - Hughes, Ted, Angling permits, 1987-1988 (Box 180, Folder 8)
  - Hughes, Ted, Artwork (Box 180, Folder 9)
  - Hughes, Ted, Biographical sketch, ca. 1991 (Box 180, Folder 10)
  - Hughes, Ted, Permit to exit and re-enter U.S., 1959 (Box 180, Folder 11)
  - Hughes, Ted, Royal Air Force Certificate of Service (Box 180, Folder 12)
  - Hughes, Ted, "Service of Thanksgiving for the Life and Work of Ted Hughes," May 13, 1999, program [See also Series 9: Audiovisual material, "Service of Thanksgiving for the Life and Work of Ted Hughes"] (Box 180, Folder 13)
  - Hughes, Ted, (U.S.) Social Security card (Box 180, Folder 14)
  - Hughes, Ted and Sylvia Plath, "Unto Your Live's End: A Marriage Address [from R. Mercer Wilson, rector], June 16, 1956 (Box 180, Folder 15)
  - Hughes, Ted and Sylvia Plath, Marriage Certificate, June 16, 1957 (Box 180, Folder 16)
  - Hughes, Ted and Sylvia Plath, Marriage poem, MS in wedding card, written by Lucas Myers and Daniel Huws, 1957 (Box 180, Folder 17)
  - Hughes, William Henry, WWI scrapbook containing newspaper clippings and photographs (Box 180, Folder 18)
  - Plath, Sylvia, Death Certificate, March 1, 1963 (Box 180, Folder 19)
  - Plath, Sylvia, Driving License (British), 1961 (Box 180, Folder 20)
  - Plath, Sylvia, Smallpox vaccination record, July 6, 1959 (Box 180, Folder 21)
  - Plath, Sylvia, U.S. Passport, 1959 (Box 180, Folder 22)
  - Wevill, Assia, Drawing (photocopy of Emily Dickinson poem on back with one stanza circled by Wevill; TH writing: "By Assia"), 1960s (Box 180, Folder 23)
  - Memorabilia
  - Children's Artwork-unidentified (Box 181, Folder 1)
  - "Coin (gone) from Irene Worth (after 'Oedipus')" (Box 181, Folder 2)
  - Epitaph for Robert Farrar (Box 181, Folder 3)
  - Hanbury Manor, Hertfordshire, England, numbered print, artist unknown (Box OP118)
  - "The Horses," handwritten excerpt on photograph (Box OP119)
  - Lock of hair (child's?) (Box 181, Folder 4)
  - Checkbook (Sylvia Plath's), billfold, and glasses case (Box 181, Folder 5)
- Audio-visual materials, Series 9; DVD1-3; CD1-41
  The series consists of audio-visual materials relating to Ted Hughes including audiocassettes, videotapes, and a motion picture film. The majority of the audiocassettes are of Ted Hughes dictating Shakespeare and the Goddess of Complete Being to a typist which includes all capitalization, punctuation, etc. Chapter numbers are based on Ted Hughes' dictation; some may be incorrect. Other audiocassettes include a 1963 British Broadcasting Corporation interview with Sylvia Plath from BBC Sound Archives and "Service of Thanksgiving for the Life and Work of Ted Hughes," 13 May 1999. The motion picture film dipicts a Mexborough Grammar School field trip to Switzerland in 1949.
  - Ted Hughes dictating Shakespeare and the Goddess of Complete Being
  - Introduction [digitized; Emory:b7hd1] (Box -, Folder -)
  - Introduction [digitized; Emory:b7h1h] (Box -, Folder -)
  - Tape 1, Side A [chapter 1] [digitized; Emory:b7d85] (Box -, Folder -)
  - Tape 2, Side A [chapter 1] [digitized; Emory:b7dck] (Box -, Folder -)
  - Tape 3, side A [chapter 1] [digitized; Emory:b7dfv] (Box -, Folder -)
  - Tape 3, side B [chapter 1] [digitized; Emory:b7dh4] (Box -, Folder -)
  - Tape 4, side A [appendix, chapter 2, chapter 3] [digitized; Emory:b7dkd] (Box -, Folder -)
  - Tape 4, side B [chapter 3, chapter 4] [digitized; Emory:b7dnp] (Box -, Folder -)
  - Tape 5, side A [chapter 4, section 3 chapter 5, chapter 8, chapter 11] [digitized; Emory:b7dr3] (Box -, Folder -)
  - Tape 5, side B [chapter 7, chapter 12] [digitized; Emory:b7dvh] (Box -, Folder -)
  - Tape 6, side A [chapter 12, chapter 14] [digitized; Emory:b7f60] (Box -, Folder -)
  - Tape 6, side B [chapter 14, chapter 15, chapter 16, section 4] [digitized; Emory:b7f9d] (Box -, Folder -)
  - Tape 7, side A [chapter 22, chapter 23, chapter 24] [digitized; Emory:b7fh7] (Box -, Folder -)
  - Tape 7, side B [chapter 24, chapter 25] [digitized; Emory:b7fkh] (Box -, Folder -)
  - Chapter 25B-25C [digitized; Emory:b7hg9] (Box -, Folder -)
  - Chapter 25C-25D [digitized; Emory:b7hjk] (Box -, Folder -)
  - Chapter 25D [digitized; Emory:b7h3s] (Box -, Folder -)
  - Tape 8, side A [chapter 25] [digitized; Emory:b7fcp] (Box -, Folder -)
  - Tape 9, side B [section 5, chapter 27] [digitized; Emory:b7ffz] (Box -, Folder -)
  - Tape 9, side A [chapter 27, chapter 29] [digitized; Emory:b7fpx] (Box -, Folder -)
  - Tape 9, side B [chapter 29] [digitized; Emory:b7fr6] (Box -, Folder -)
  - Tape 10, side A [chapter 30, chapter 31, chapter 32] [digitized; Emory:b7gjg] (Box -, Folder -)
  - Tape 10, side B [chapter 32, chapter 33, chapter 34, chapter 35] [digitized; Emory:b75z6] (Box -, Folder -)
  - Tape 11, side A [chapter 35, chapter 36, chapter 37, chapter 38, chapter 39] [digitized; Emory:b7gnw] (Box -, Folder -)
  - Tape 11, side B [chapter 39, chapter 40, chapter 41] [digitized; Emory:b7gq5] (Box -, Folder -)
  - Tape 12, side A [chapters unknown] [digitized; Emory:b7dzx] (Box -, Folder -)
  - Tape 12, side B [chapters unknown] [digitized; Emory:b7f19] (Box -, Folder -)
  - Tape 13, side A [chapter 44, chapter 45, chapter 46, chapter 47] [digitized; Emory:b7gsf] (Box -, Folder -)
  - Tape 13, side B [chapter 47, chapter 48] [digitized; Emory:b7gwv] (Box -, Folder -)
  - Tape 14, side A [chapters unknown] [digitized; Emory:b7f3k] (Box -, Folder -)
  - Tape 14, side B [chapter 53] [digitized; Emory:b7d5r] (Box -, Folder -)
  - Tape 15, side A [chapter 53, chapter 54] [digitized; Emory:b7hbr] (Box -, Folder -)
  - Tape 15, side B [chapter 54, chapter 55, chapter 56] [digitized; Emory:b7hcw] (Box -, Folder -)
  - Tape 16 [chapter 56, chapter 57] [digitized; Emory:b7gz4] (Box -, Folder -)
  - Text beginning, "VENUS AND ADONIS, new paragraph, He knew this myth from Greek and Latin Contexts, though his feeling for it..." [digitized; Emory:b7hkq] (Box -, Folder -)
  - Text beginning, "Years ago, in a brief note to an Anthology, capital A, of Shakespeare's, capital S, verse, I made an observation about a basic structural pattern, and a fundamental dramatic idea..." [digitized; Emory:b7h52] (Box -, Folder -)
  - "Urgent", tape beginning, "This is a piece that I'd like you to do before you do anything else... It's the same - similar - material to the rest of the papers, but it's a separate article... In a brief introduction..." [filename: b7h66] (Box -, Folder -)
  - "Urgent" [cont'd] [filename: b7h7b] (Box -)
  - Other
  - "The Poet Speaks," Sylvia Plath interviewed by Peter Orr, BBC, 30 October 1962 [digitized; Emory:b7h8g] (Box -, Folder -)
  - "Service of Thanksgiving for the Life and Work of Ted Hughes," 13 May 1999 [1 of 2] [See also Series 8: Personal effects and memorabilia, "Service of Thanksgiving for the Life and Work of Ted Hughes, program"] [digitized; Emory:b7hn0] (Box -, Folder -)
  - "Service of Thanksgiving for the Life and Work of Ted Hughes," 13 May 1999 [2 of 2] [See also Series 8: Personal effects and memorabilia, "Service of Thanksgiving for the Life and Work of Ted Hughes, program"] [digitized; Emory:b7hp4] (Box -, Folder -)
  - Videocassettes-Ted Hughes work
  - Hedger, Ray - "Crow" (1981) [a free interpretation of the book Crow by Ted Hughes] (Box DVD1)
  - Bryant, Christopher - "Relic" (1982) [Film accompanied by poems of Ted Hughes] (Box DVD2)
  - Motion picture films
  - Mexborough Grammar School field trip to Switzerland, 1949 (Box DVD3)
- Collected materials, Series 10; Box 182-183
  The collected materials located in Series 10 include correspondence and other material acquired from various sources. It is primarily composed of letters written by Hughes with some accompanying enclosures. This correspondence has been arranged alphabetically and chronologically by the last name of the correspondent. The one exception is a set of letters regarding the 1967 Poetry International Festival which Ted Hughes helped organize. This correspondence, including letters from Yehuda Amichai, W.H. Auden, Allen Ginsberg, Pablo Neruda, and others, are grouped alphabetically under Poetry International. The series also includes a manuscript of Her Husband: Hughes and Plath: A Marriage by Diane Middlebrook and a copybook kept by Enid Wilkinson containing two early Ted Hughes poems written in his hand. For details regarding the provenance of specific items in this artificially assembled portion of the collection, consult the library staff.
  Arranged by accession.
  - Graham Akryod correspondence, 1992-1998 (Accession 2001/10-09
  - Ted Hughes to Graham Akryod, 22 October 1992, ALS (Box 182, Folder 1)
  - Ted Hughes to Graham Akryod, 2 October 1993, ALS (Box 182, Folder 1)
  - Ted Hughes to Graham Akryod, 31 January 1998, ALS (Box 182, Folder 1)
  - Christopher Barker correspondence, 1982-1986 (Accession 98-10-04) [See also Subseries 1.3: General Correspondence, January-March 1980, July 1985, and August 1986]
  - Christopher Barker to Ted Hughes, 12 November 1980, TL, 1 p. (Box 182, Folder 2)
  - Ted Hughes to Christopher Barker, 21 November 1980, ALS, 1 p. (Box 182, Folder 2)
  - Christopher Barker to Ted Hughes, 27 November 1980, TL, 1 p. (Box 182, Folder 2)
  - Ted Hughes to Christopher Barker, 19 June 1981, 2 pp. (Box 182, Folder 2)
  - Christopher Barker to Ted Hughes, 17 June 1981, TL, 1 p. (Box 182, Folder 2)
  - Christopher Barker to Ted Hughes, 23 June 1981, TL, 2 pp. (Box 182, Folder 2)
  - Christopher Barker to Ted Hughes, 23 June 1982, TL, 1 p. (Box 182, Folder 2)
  - Carol Hughes to Christopher Barker, 28 June 1982, TLS, 1 p. (Box 182, Folder 2)
  - Christopher Barker to Ted Hughes, 30 June 1982, TL, 1 p. (Box 182, Folder 2)
  - Michael Schmidt [Carcanet Press] to TH, 2 July 1985, TL, 1 p. (Box 182, Folder 2)
  - Christopher Barker to Ted Hughes, 10 July 1985 TN, 1 p. (Box 182, Folder 2)
  - Carol Hughes to Christopher Barker, 29 July 1985, TNS, 1 p. (Box 182, Folder 2)
  - Christopher Barker to Ted Hughes, 12 February 1986, TL, 1 p. (Box 182, Folder 2)
  - Carol Hughes to Christopher Barker, 30 April 1986, postcard (Box 182, Folder 2)
  - Ted Hughes to Christopher Barker, 5 August 1986, ALS, 2 pp. (Box 182, Folder 2)
  - Christopher Barker to Ted Hughes, 4 August 1986, TL, 1 p. (Box 182, Folder 2)
  - Christopher Barker to Ted Hughes, 6 August 1986, TL, 1 p. (Box 182, Folder 2)
  - Olwyn Hughes to Christopher Barker, 9 August 1986, notecard (Box 182, Folder 2)
  - Olwyn Hughes to Robyn Marsak, 10 December 1986, TLS, 1 p. (Box 182, Folder 2)
  - Gene Baro Correspondence, n.d. (Accession 2001-10-04)
  - Ted Hughes to Gene Barp, n.d., 9 pp. (contains TS of "Pibroch," "Gog," "out," "Kreutzer Sonata," "Wodwo," "The Howling of Wolves," "Full Moon," and "Cadenza") (Box 182, Folder 3)
  - Michael Dawson correspondence, 1972-1983 (accession 87-01-12)
  - Ted Hughes to Michael Dawson, 6 October 1972, TLS, 1 p. (Box 182, Folder 4)
  - Ted Hughes to Michael Dawson, 21 June 1974, ALS, 2 pp. (Box 182, Folder 4)
  - Ted Hughes to Michael Dawson, 7 October 1974, ALS, 2 pp. (Box 182, Folder 4)
  - Ted Hughes to Michael Dawson, 18 January 1975, TLS, 1 p. (Box 182, Folder 4)
  - Ted Hughes to Michael Dawson, 15 February 1975, TLS, 1 p. (Box 182, Folder 4)
  - Ted Hughes to Michael Dawson, 5 March [1975], TLS, 2 pp. (Box 182, Folder 4)
  - Ted Hughes to Michael Dawson, 2 July 1975, TLS, 1 p. (Box 182, Folder 4)
  - Ted Hughes to Michael Dawson, 17 June 1981, ALS, 2 pp. (Box 182, Folder 4)
  - Ted Hughes to Michael Dawson, 29 January 1982, ANS, 1 p. (Box 182, Folder 4)
  - Ted Hughes to Michael Dawson, 10 October 1982, ALS, 3 pp. (Box 182, Folder 4)
  - Ted Hughes to Michael Dawson, 1 February 1983, ALS, 2 pp. (Box 182, Folder 4)
  - Ted Hughes to Michael Dawson, n.d., ALS, 1 p. (Box 182, Folder 4)
  - BBC radio script enclosed with Michael Dawson correspondence (accession 87-01-12)
  - Cave Birds, ca. 1975, radio script w/ holograph notes and additions, 31 pp. (Box 182, Folder 5)
  - Joseph Gold/Winnie Myers correspondence, 1962-1964 (accession 99-01-04)
  - Ted Hughes to Winnie Myers, 14 August 1962, TL, 1 p. (Box 182, Folder 6)
  - Winnie Myers to Joseph Gold, 7 December 1962, TLS, 1 p. (Box 182, Folder 6)
  - Invoice, 6 February 1964 (Box 182, Folder 6)
  - Winnie Myers to Joseph Gold, 14 February 1964, TLS, 1 p. (Box 182, Folder 6)
  - Winnie Myers to Joseph Gold, 6 April 1964, TNS, 1 p. (Box 182, Folder 6)
  - Winnie Myers to Joseph Gold, 22 April 1964, TNS, 1 p. (Box 182, Folder 6)
  - Joseph Gold to Winnie Myers, 27 April 1964, TL (carbon), 1 p. (Box 182, Folder 6)
  - Winnie Myers to Joseph Gold, 19 May 1964, TLS, 1 p. (Box 182, Folder 6)
  - Joseph Gold to Winnie Myers H, 25 May 1964, TL (carbon), 1 p. (Box 182, Folder 6)
  - Ted Hughes to Joseph Gold, [28 July 1964], TLS, 1 p. (Box 182, Folder 6)
  - Joseph Gold to Ted Hughes, 3 August 1964, TL (carbon), 1 p. (Box 182, Folder 6)
  - Ted Hughes to Joseph Gold, [7 August 1964] ALS, 1 p. (Box 182, Folder 6)
  - 1963 Newspaper clippings re Ted Hughes (Box 182, Folder 6)
  - Joseph Gold/Richard Gilbertson correspondence, (accessioned 2005)
  - Richard Gilbertson / Joseph Gold correspondence, 1967-1973 (Box 182, Folder 7)
  - Dora M. Pettinelia to Ted Hughes, 6 April 1964 (Box 182, Folder 8)
  - Ted Hughes to Dora M. Pettinelia, 12 October 1964, 1 p. (Box 182, Folder 8)
  - Dora M. Pettinelia to Ted Hughes, 25 February 1969 (Box 182, Folder 8)
  - Ted Hughes to Michael Dyton [includes two riddles], Spring/Summer 1966, 2 pp. and sketch of Michael Dyton by Ted Hughes, November 1966 (Box 182, Folder 9)
  - Assia Weevil to Richard Gilbertson, 16 September 1968, 1 p. (Box 182, Folder 10)
  - Ted Hughes to Richard Gilbertson, [March 1969], 1 p. [mentions Assia's death] (Box 182, Folder 11)
  - Flyer, The Poets' Theatre, The Calm by Ted Hughes, [1961] and clipping "The Poets' Theatre Workshop, The Yardling, 30 November 1961 (Box 182, Folder 12)
  - Catalog: Richard Gilberton, Catalogue Twenty-One, 1966 [includes Hughes item for sale] (Box 182, Folder 13)
  - Catalog, The Manuscript Series, Richard Gilbertson, June 1969 [includes sale of Animal Poems, Five Autumn Songs for Children's Voices, and The Martyrdom of Bishop Farrar] (Box 182, Folder 14)
  - BBC Contract, "Snow" - 'Write and read,' 19 November 1962 (Box 182, Folder 15)
  - Sketch of Ted Hughes, artist unknown (Box 182, Folder 16)
  - Rosaleen McCoola correspondence, 1957-1959 (accession 2003-08-02)
  - Ted Hughes to Rosaleen McCoola, 17 November 1957, 1 p. (Box 182, Folder 17)
  - Ted Hughes to Rosaleen McCoola, 14 December 1957, 1 p. (Box 182, Folder 17)
  - Ted Hughes to Rosaleen McCoola, 22 December 1957, 1 page (Box 182, Folder 17)
  - Ted Hughes to Rosaleen McCoola, n.d., 1 p. with TS of "Quest" (Box 182, Folder 17)
  - Norman Nicholson to Rosaleen McCoola, 27 November 1958, 2 pp. (Box 182, Folder 18)
  - Norman Nicholson to Rosaleen McCoola, 7 December 1958, 2 pp. (Box 182, Folder 18)
  - Norman Nicholson to Rosaleen McCoola, 8 December 1958, postcard (Box 182, Folder 18)
  - Norman Nicholson to Rosaleen McCoola, 12 December 1958, 2 pp. (Box 182, Folder 18)
  - Norman Nicholson to Rosaleen McCoola, 24 December 1958, 1 p. (Box 182, Folder 18)
  - Norman Nicholson to Rosaleen McCoola, 9 January 1959, 3 pp. (Box 182, Folder 18)
  - Norman Nicholson to Rosaleen McCoola, 23 January 1959, 1 p. (Box 182, Folder 18)
  - Norman Nicholson to Rosaleen McCoola, January 1959, permissions correspondence (Box 182, Folder 18)
  - John O'Meara correspondence, 1996-1998 (accession 2003-08-03)
  - Ted Hughes to John O'Meara, 21 November 1996, 1 notecard and 5 March 1998, 2 pp. (Box 182, Folder 19)
  - Poetry International correspondence and materials (accession 87-01-09)
  - Bella Akmadulina to TH, n.d., ALS, 2 pp. (Box 182, Folder 20)
  - Rafael Alberti to TH, 1 November 1966, 1 p. and 24 May 1967, 1 p. (Box 182, Folder 21)
  - Yehuda Amichai to TH, 26 April 1967, ALS, 2 pp.; 30 April 1967, ALS, 1 p.; 6 May 1967, ALS, 1 p.; and 31 May 1967, TLS, 1 p. (Box 182, Folder 22)
  - W.H. Auden to TH, 1 October 1966, ALS, 1 p. (Box 182, Folder 23)
  - Ingeborg Bachman to TH, 25 June 1967, telegram, 1 p.; 26 June 1967, TLS, 1 p.; 9 July 1967, telegram, 1 p.; and n.d., telegram, 1 p. (Box 182, Folder 24)
  - John Berryman to TH, 7 June 1967, telegram, 1 p. (Box 182, Folder 25)
  - Yves Bonnefoy to TH, 31 May 1967, ALS, 1 p. and 5 July 1967, ALS, 2 pp. (Box 182, Folder 26)
  - Basil Bunting to TH, 16 April 1967, ALS, 1 p. (Box 182, Folder 27)
  - Austin Clarke to TH, June 1967, ALS, 1 p. (Box 182, Folder 28)
  - Lawrence Durrell to TH, 6 March 1967, TNS, 1 p. (Box 182, Folder 29)
  - Hans Magnus Enzensberger to TH, 29 January 1967, TLS, 1 p.; 15 May 1967, TLS, 1 p.; 10 June 1967, postcard; and 23 June 1967, telegram (Box 182, Folder 30)
  - Allen Ginsberg to TH, 5 October 1966, TLS, 1 p.; 16 March 1967, ALS, 1 p.; 5 May 1967, ALS, 1 p.; 9 May 1967, ALS, 1 p.; 17 June 1967, TLS, 1 p. w/ TNS, 1 p.; and 26 July 1967, ANS, 1 p. (Box 182, Folder 31)
  - Robert Graves to TH, 21 May 1967, ALS, 1 p. (Box 182, Folder 32)
  - Michael Hamberger to TH, n.d., ALS, 1 p. (Box 182, Folder 33)
  - Anthony Hecht to TH, 1 November 1966, TLS, 1 p. and 22 June 1967, ALS, 1 p. (Box 182, Folder 34)
  - Zbigniew Herbert to TH, 27 November 1966, TLS, 1 p. and 1 April 1967, TLS, 1 p. (Box 182, Folder 35)
  - Miroslav Holub to TH, 21 March 1967, TLS, 1 p. (Box 182, Folder 36)
  - Anne Sexton and Lois Ames to TH, 20 July 1967, telegram (Box 182, Folder 37)
  - Hugh McDiarmid to TH, 20 March 1967, ALS, 1 p. and 21 March 1967, postcard (Box 182, Folder 38)
  - Pablo Neruda to TH, 24 September 1966, ALS, 1 p. and 14 June 1967, telegram (Box 182, Folder 39)
  - George Seferis to TH, 7 February 1967, ALS, 1 p. and 18 May 1967, ALS, 1 p. (Box 182, Folder 40)
  - Stephen Spender to TH, 18 May 1967, ALS, 1 p. (Box 182, Folder 41)
  - Guiseppe Ugaretti to TH, 8 October 1966, TLS, 1 p. (Box 182, Folder 42)
  - Andrei Vosnosensky to TH, 11 July 1967, telegram (Box 182, Folder 43)
  - Arnold Wesker to TH, 29 March 1967, TLS, 1 p. (Box 182, Folder 44)
  - Yevegny Yevkeschenko to TH, 5 July 1967, telegram (Box 182, Folder 45)
  - Manuscript and typescript drafts of programs (Box 182, Folder 46)
  - Programs and information sheets (Box 182, Folder 47)
  - Sonia Raiziss Correspondence, 1959 (accession 99-05-06)
  - Ted Hughes to Sonia Raiziss, 22 December 1959, TLS, 1 p. (Box 182, Folder 48)
  - Patricia Tormey correspondence, 1969
  - Ted Hughes to Patricia Tormey, [Spring 1969] (Box 182, Folder 49)
  - Precious Stones: Their Occult Power and Hidden Significance, with inscription by Ted Hughes, 29 May 1969 (Box 182, Folder 50)
  - W. Price Turner Correspondence, 1962 (accession 99-03-11)
  - Ted Hughes to Bill Turner, 5 April 1962, TLS, 1 p. (Box 182, Folder 51)
  - Unidentified Correspondents
  - Ted Hughes to "Harriet" [?], 5 December [n.y.], ALS, 1 p. (accession 99-03-11) and (Box 182, Folder 52)
  - Ted Hughes to "Harriet" [?], 11 March [n.y.], ALS, 1 p. (accession 99-03-11) (Box 182, Folder 52)
  - Manuscript: Dianne Middlebrook: Her Husband: Hughes and Plath: A Marriage [accession 2005-04-04]
  - Draft, chapter 1-2, April 21, 2003 (Box 183, Folder 1)
  - Draft, chapter 3-5, April 21, 2003 (Box 183, Folder 2)
  - Draft, chapter 6-7, April 21, 2003 (Box 183, Folder 3)
  - Draft, chapter 8-11, April 21, 2003 (Box 183, Folder 4)
  - Cover mock-up (Box 183, Folder 5)
  - Advance proof copy, 2003 (Box 183, Folder 6)
  - Enid Wilkinson copybook, circa 1950-1951 [accession 2006-08-03]
  - Notebook containing two Ted Hughes poems in his hand, [circa 1950-1951] (Box 183, Folder 7)
  - John Haffenden correspondence, 1980 [accession 2006-09-06]
  - Ted Hughes to John Haffenden, 10 March 1980, 18 November 1980 (Box 183, Folder 8)
  - Sir Christopher Lever correspondence / Rhino Rescue Auction, 1986-1997 [accession 2007-07-07]
  - Ted Hughes to Sir Christopher Lever concerning the Rhino Rescue Auction and his poem, "The Black Rhino," 28 October 1986-15 October 1997 (Box 183, Folder 9)
  - Photocopy of Ted Hughes' poem, "The Black Rhino" (Box 183, Folder 10)
  - Sotheby's Rhino Rescue Auction booklet, 1987 (Box 183, Folder 11)
  - Newspaper clippings concerning the Rhino Rescue Auction (Box 183, Folder 12)